A team of Cambridge psychologists conducted an experiment to compare the cognitive effects of merely seeing art with actively judging how beautiful it is.
剑桥大学的一个心理学家团队开展了一项实验，比较仅仅观看艺术与主动评判艺术之美对认知产生的不同影响。
In the study, 187 people were invited to visit Kettle’s Yard gallery during an exhibition of handmade clay objects.
在研究中，187人受邀在一场手工陶土作品展期间参观了凯特尔庭院美术馆。
Participants were randomly divided into two groups: the “beauty” group was asked to actively consider and then rate the beauty of each object they viewed, while the control group just matched a line drawing of the object with the artwork itself.
参与者被随机分成两组：“美感组”被要求主动思考，并给所看到的每件作品的美打分；而对照组只需把作品的线描图和作品本身配对。
All participants were then tested on how they process information, and whether it’s in a more practical or abstract way.
随后，所有参与者都接受了测试，看他们如何处理信息，是更偏向实际的方式，还是更抽象的方式。
Across all participants, those in the beauty group scored almost 14% higher on average than the control group in abstract thinking.
从全体参与者来看，美感组在抽象思维上的得分平均比对照组高出近14%。
While they were told the study was about cognitive processes, participants were asked about interests, with around half saying they had an artistic hobby.
虽然参与者被告知这项研究是关于认知过程的，但他们也被问及兴趣爱好，约一半人说自己有艺术方面的爱好。
Among those, the effect was greater: those with an artistic hobby in the beauty group scored over 25% higher on average for abstract thinking than those with an artistic hobby in the control group.
在这些人当中，效果更明显：美感组中有艺术爱好的人，抽象思维平均得分比对照组中有艺术爱好的人高出25%以上。
Emotional states of participants were also measured by asking about their feelings while completing the gallery task.
研究人员还通过询问参与者完成美术馆任务时的感受，测量了他们的情绪状态。
Across all participants, those in the beauty group reported an average of 23% higher levels of “transformative and self-transcendent feelings” — such as feeling moved, enlightened and inspired — than the control group.
从全体参与者来看，美感组报告的“转变性和自我超越的感受”——比如被感动、受启迪、受鼓舞——平均比对照组高出23%。
Importantly, however, the beauty group did not report feeling any happier than the control group, suggesting that it was the engagement with beauty that influenced abstract thinking, rather than any overall positivity from the experience.
但重要的是，美感组并没有表示自己比对照组更快乐，这说明影响抽象思维的是对美的投入，而不是这次体验带来的整体积极情绪。
“We usually think in very concrete terms when doing something on a screen,” said Simone Schnall, senior author of the study.
“我们在屏幕上做事时，通常是用非常具体的方式思考，”该研究的资深作者西蒙娜·施纳尔说。
“It’s becoming much rarer to zone out and just let the mind wander, but that’s when we think in ways that broaden our minds.
“放空自己、任思绪漫游的时候越来越少了，但恰恰是在那种时候，我们的思考方式能开阔思维。
Admiring the beauty of art may be the ideal way to initiate the abstract cognitive processes.”
欣赏艺术之美，可能是开启抽象认知过程的理想方式。”